Guide to the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Yale University, Records Concerning Research Projects and Grants Conducted by Faculty
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Yale University, records concerning research projects and grants conducted by faculty
1959-1973
RU 39
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(22 boxes)
The records consist of proposals, reports, correspondence, financial records, contracts, and related materials concerning research conducted by the faculty of the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies (called the School of Forestry prior to 1972).
Yale University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 20-D (YRG 20-D), Records of committees of the Yale School of Art.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by granting agency or project title.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of proposals, reports, correspondence, financial records, contracts, and related materials concerning research conducted by the faculty of the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies (called the School of Forestry prior to 1972).
Forests and forestry -- Research; Human ecology -- Study and teaching; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies; Yale University. School of Forestry
- Faculty research reports and writings, 1959-1973; Accession 1982-A-017
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Adirondack Study Commission: Rockefeller, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Philosophical Society: Michaux Fund--Dr. Ledig, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Atomic Energy Commission
    - Administration, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 5)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Expenditures, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Final Report, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Progress Reports and Renewal Proposal
      - 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bibliography of Books on Forestry by Faculty and Alumni, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Biometeorology
    - Correspondence: University Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Proposal: University Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Canada/Department of Forestry and Rural Development: Regional Direction, Maritimes Region. Henson, Mott, Farnival, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Canadian Wildlife Service: Richard S. Miller--"A Study of Age Ratio's in Sandhill Cranes", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Con Edison--Borman Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Connecticut Department of Environmental Protection: Proposal on Muskrats P.A.J., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Connecticut Research Commission
    - "Analysis Demand for Recreation," A. C. Warrill, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Attenuation of Solar Beam by Pollution," Reifsnyder, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Chemistry of a Pine Sawfly", 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "Forest Sunflecks…," Reifsnyder, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Lead and Sodium Contamination, W. H. Smith, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Photosynthesis, Translocation, and Dry Matter Production", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "Photosynthesis, Translocation, and Dry Matter Production": Trip, Bodkin, Ledig, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Thomas Siccama, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "The Significance of Root Exudation in the Decline of Connecticut Hardwoods," W. H. Smith, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Conservation Foundation--Biometeorology: Benson and Reifsnyder, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Consortium for Environmental Forestry
    - "The Hemlock--Hardwood Forests of the Northeastern Megalopolis", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Albert C. Warrill, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cornell University/Yale/IBM/U.S. Dept. of Interior: Water Resources Research: Botkin, Likens, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Dutch Elm Disease--DDT, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Environmental Protection Agency: "Heavy Metals: Quantities, Cycles, etc." W. H. Smith, T. G. Siccama, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Esso (Exxon) Foundation "T.V. Proposal", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Grant and Contract Administration, Yale University: F. H. Bormann "The role of allelopathy...", 1968 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - John A. Hartford Foundation
    - Correspondence, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Monthly Statements, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - International Biological Program: Bormann (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - National Science Foundation
    - Environmental Biology Program: Bormann and Liken, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 40 - 41)
    - Graduate Research in Ecology Proposal, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Grants Pending, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Grant Proposals Rejected, 1961-1966 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - GP 4239 Relfsnyder, "Activation and Instrumentation of a Low-Speed Wind Tunnel", undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - GB-2841, "Analysis of Genetic and Environmental Components of Phenotypic Expression in Forest Trees," Mergen, 1964-1968 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - "Attenuation of Solar Beam by Pollution", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - G19973 Mergen, "Basic Research in Forest Genetics", 1960-1964 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - G8891 "Basic Research in Forest Genetics," Mergen, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - GB3653 "The Behavior of Neodiprion," Henson, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - "Comparative Ecology of Inter-species Competition," Richard S. Miller, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - "A Comparative Study of Territoriality in Dragonflies," R. S. Miller, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - "Dragonflies Studies," Miller, Connor, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - "Ecology of Photosynthesis and Respiration in Forest Trees," Bourdeau G-13971, 1960-1967 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - G14081 Reifsnyder finances: "Energy Budget of a Forest", 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - G14081 Reifsnyder "Energy Budget of a Forest" proposal, correspondence, results, finances, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - 0858 "An experimental analysis…of the pine leaf Aphid Pineus Pinifoliae," Handon and Lowe, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - "Field Measurement of Northern Hardwood Photosynthesis", 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - "Forest Sunflicks," Reifsnyder, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - "Forest Tree Root Exudates," W. H. Smith, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Greeley Memorial Laboratory, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - "Habitat Relationships Gir Forest," P. A. Jordan, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Botkln, W. Smith "Influence Selected Air…", 1969 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - "An Interdisciplinary Study of Adaptations to Social Change"--Forestry and Sociology Depts., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - "Land Use Management," Burch, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - "Land Use Management," Mergen, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - G-23911 Richards, "Mechanisms of Nitrogen Fixation in Pineas", 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - "Optional Niche Space of Redwing Blackbirds," R. S. Miller, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - "Pathways, Sinks, and Effects of Lead and other Heavy Metals, etc.," W. H. Smith, Thomas G. Siccama, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - R. Clarke Miller: Dissertation Research; "Population Regulation in Fowler's Toad", 1971 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - "Post-pollination Reproductive Physiology," Mr. Ledig, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - "Heavy Metal Quantities, Cycles and Significance," W. H. Smith, Siccama, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - World Wildlife Foundation: Red Wolf Study, Jordan and Shaw, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - "Post-exudates and their significance in the ecology of selected root pathogens," W. H. Smith, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Course--"Solar and Terrestrial Radiation Processes", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - "…Solar Radiation…", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - "Structure of Cell Walls," Berlyn, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - G-23639 Voigt: "Studies of Soil-Root Relationships in Ion Uptake by Forest Trees", 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - "Values, Social Change, and Land Use: A Sociological Analysis," Burch, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - "New Cities", 1969 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - New Haven Foundation--Enriching Environmental Education the New Haven Area, Bormann, Voigt, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Office of Naval Research: Phase-out of research project in tropical wood, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 82 - 83)
  - Organization of Tropical Studies: F. H. Bormann, G. M. Woodwell; Turrialba, Costa Rica, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Provost's Office--Academic Appointments and Changes, 1961-1969 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Public Health Service: Training Grant, Biometeorology, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Reports, Naval Research
    - Contr. 609 (13) project 330-001, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Contr. 609 (13) project 330-001, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Research and Teaching Funds, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Revisions of Appendices A and B of Nad Crane, Cooperative Fish and Wildlife Plan, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 90 - 91)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Forestry Education in Latin America, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Scott Paper Company's Research Division: re. Grant for research in wood technology, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Smithsonian--Jordan: Gir Forest Travel and Foreign Exchange Policy, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Smithsonian--Jordan: Gir Forest, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - State University College of Forestry: V. P. for Research; Consortium for Environmental Forestry, Burch, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - U. S. Department of Transportation, "Metal Pollution Associated with Motor Vehicles," W. H. Smith, Siccama, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - U. S. Forest Service
    - Cooperative Agreements; Southern Forest Experiment Station, Wangaard, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - "Environmental Alteration…" W. H. Smith, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - Forest Fire Research; Reifsnyder, Southern Forestry Experiment Station, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Forest Genetics Research, Mergen, Southern Forest Experiment Station, 1961-1969 (Box 10, Folder 101)
    - Agreement with Yale; Northeastern Forestry Experiment Station, 1957-1971 (Box 10, Folder 102)
    - "Personal and Social Functions of…Experiences in Natural Settings for Inner City Children", 1970 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - United States Department of Agriculture: "Physiological Models of Genetic Variation in Dry Matter Production," F. Thomas Ledig, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - U. S. Forestry Service
    - Henson and Mergen, Sawfly Study, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Wood Technology Research, Wangaard and Kellogg, 1965-1970 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Yale School of Forestry/Institute of Social Research: "Study of the Human Community and Ecosystem," W. R. Burch, undated (Box 11, Folder 107)